skillsurvey.com 2018-11-16

# Privacy Policy | SkillSurvey

### The SkillSurvey System

SkillSurvey provides a web-based service that enables people who have worked with an individual to provide confidential feedback on the individual’s competencies for a specific job. Additionally, SkillSurvey provides services related to physician credentialing for healthcare providers.

Organizations and individuals (Subscribers) use the service to send emails or text messages to the job candidate and the candidate’s references. The reference email or text contains a link to a web-based survey, which the reference then completes and submits electronically.

Candidate reports are either generated automatically or monitored and finalized by customer personnel (such as HR staff, recruiters, hiring managers, etc.).

This Privacy Policy describes the way we collect, use, and secure your personal information, both through our web-based service and on our website, www.skillsurvey.com (together, “SkillSurvey”). By using the SkillSurvey services, you consent to this Privacy Policy.

### General Security Policy

Your privacy is our top concern. We work hard to earn and keep your trust, so we adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:

  * We will only receive the minimum personal information required to successfully complete the SkillSurvey reference checking process for our Subscribers
  * We will never rent or sell the personally identifiable information of any user of our system (e.g. recruiter, candidate, reference, etc.) to third parties for their own marketing purposes
  * Any sensitive information that you provide will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology

Notice of all changes that materially affect ways in which your personally identifiable data may be used or shared will be posted in updates to our Privacy Policy or as otherwise required by applicable law. If you continue to use the SkillSurvey service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on our site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices.

### Information Collection

SkillSurvey does not collect personally identifying information from visitors to our website or service unless specifically provided by our customers, their employees or representatives, their job or credentialing candidates, or the candidate’s references. Personally identifiable information includes name, email address, mobile telephone number, and other data elements requested by our customers or required to perform the SkillSurvey services.

##### For Candidate Reference Services

We receive personally identifiable information about you and your references in order to perform the SkillSurvey reference checking process for our customers.

SkillSurvey may receive background/demographic information, on a voluntary or optional basis, from job candidates. This information will not be associated with the candidate’s name, email address, or any other personally identifying information. This information will not be shared with a prospective employer. It will be used by SkillSurvey solely to monitor compliance with U.S. federal statutes and for other research purposes.

##### For Physician Credentialing Services

We receive personally identifiable information from physicians on behalf of certain healthcare providers for the provider’s use in the credentialing process. The information includes name, contact information, education, work and training history, references as well as other information customarily collected as part of a physician credentialing process.

##### For All Visitors

SkillSurvey collects IP addresses for system administration and record keeping. Your IP address is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the World Wide Web. Our servers record incoming IP addresses. The IP addresses are analyzed only for the purposes of fraud detection and service performance. (Think of an IP address like your zip code; it tells us in general terms where you’re from.)

SkillSurvey uses “cookies,” which are small pieces of information stored by your browser or other application on your computer’s browser or hard drive. We use cookies to remember certain information about visitors during their visit and may store information about your activity on the SkillSurvey application both within the same website visit and from one visit to the next. We may use cookies to recognize you and show you content on other websites based on your visits to the SkillSurvey application. The “help” portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive new cookies or how to disable cookies altogether. If you reject cookies, you may not be able to participate in certain activities or see content tailored to you. Please note that SkillSurvey does not control and do not guarantee the effectiveness of browser-based tools for managing cookies. 

SkillSurvey uses Google Analytics web analytics service offered by Google to track and report website traffic. Google Analytics may leave cookies after each session. To learn how Google Analytics collects and processes data, please visit: “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps” located at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>.

In some jurisdictions, individuals may have the right to provide opt-in consent or withdraw consent for certain uses. If you reside in such jurisdictions, such as the European Union, you may have additional rights which are detailed below, “Access, Correction and Deletion.”

### Information Use

Except as provided in this Privacy Policy, SkillSurvey does not provide or sell any of this information to third parties and will not disclose or use your personally identifiable information except to:

  * Provide customer support in successfully completing the SkillSurvey reference checking process
  * Perform statistical analyses of user behavior and characteristics
  * Measure traffic and traffic trends at this site
  * Share with our trusted partners in connection with co-promotion of the SkillSurvey application and similar products and services
  * Support and provide the products and services provided by SkillSurvey
  * Monitor compliance with applicable laws

We may provide non-identifying aggregated data about the usage of our service to third-parties for such purposes as we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate. We may segment our users by role (i.e. product managers, vice presidents), industry, geographic location, company. If you would like to be excluded from the aggregated research, please email customer service. We may also associate non-identifying information, such as IP address, with identifying information for purposes of fraud detection.

For physicians participating in a credentialing process with a healthcare provider, we will disclose information as requested by the provider, such as to peer references.

It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information when required by law. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on our company or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

We reserve the right to transfer information (including personally identifiable information) to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of SkillSurvey, or in the unlikely event of a bankruptcy, liquidation or receivership of our business. We will endeavor to provide reasonable notice of any such change in ownership of personal information.

### Communications & Opt-Out

As described above, Subscribers may use the service to communicate with job candidates and the candidate’s references through email and text message. Where applicable, candidates are required to represent and warrant that they agree to receive emails and text messages through SkillSurvey and that the references they designate also have consented to receive communications in that manner sent by or on behalf of the candidate. In particular, where candidates select text as their preferred method of contact for the candidate’s references and enter their mobile number(s), the candidate represents and warrants that each such reference has expressly consented to receive the texts from the candidate through SkillSurvey at the number provided for the purpose of job reference feedback. Note that SkillSurvey may partner with third parties to deliver and manage these communications on behalf of the candidate. The candidate and references can opt-out of these communications at any time, although doing so may impact the ability to use and benefit from SkillSurvey. Recipients of emails through SkillSurvey can opt out by clicking the opt-out link at the footer of SkillSurvey emails. Recipients of text messages can also opt-out at any time by responding S or STOP or sending S or STOP to the SkillSurvey shortcode.

### Children’s Privacy

SkillSurvey is not directed at children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from children under 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. If SkillSurvey learns that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personal information to us without parental consent, we will take all reasonable measures to delete such information from our databases and/or to not use such information for any purpose (except as necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required or allowed by law). If you become aware of any personal information we have collected from a child under 13, please contact us.

### California Residents

If you are a California resident, you may contact us to request information about circumstances in which we share certain personal information with third parties for their marketing purposes and allow third parties to collect such information. As described above, we will never rent or sell the personally identifiable information of any user of our system to third parties for their own marketing purposes. For questions, please contact us as indicated in the “Contact Us” section of this Policy.

### Do Not Track Disclosure

Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that users can set in some web browsers, allowing users to opt -out of tracking by websites and online services. At the present time, the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) has not yet established universal standards for recognizable DNT signals and therefore, we do not recognize DNT.

### Access, Correction, & Deletion

You have the right to access or correct your personal information, and can make this request by contacting the relevant SkillSurvey subscriber. That may be a recruiter or company with which you applied for a job, or a candidate who sent you a request for feedback. In addition, you may request that the Subscriber delete or restrict access to your personal data. We or the Subscriber may need to retain it for legally permitted purposes and this will be explained to you if necessary.

If you are unable to identify or contact the relevant Subscriber, you can also contact us directly by reaching out to us as described in the “Contact Us” section below.

### Retention of Personal Information

Personal information that we collect, access or process will be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfilment of the purposes for which it was collected, unless otherwise provided in agreements between SkillSurvey and its customers or as required or authorized by law. Personal information that is no longer required to fulfill the identified purposes will be destroyed, erased or made de-identified.

### Visitors from Outside the United States—Cross-Border Transfer

SkillSurvey is hosted in the United States. If you are visiting our website or using our service from outside the United States, your information may be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States or other countries in accordance with this Privacy Policy. The data protection and other applicable laws of the United States or other countries may not be as comprehensive as those laws or regulations in your country or may otherwise differ from the data protection or consumer protection laws in your country. Your information may be available to government authorities under lawful orders and law applicable in such jurisdictions. We will use an appropriate data transfer mechanism, such as the execution of Standard Contractual Clauses with our Subscribers. In addition, by using SkillSurvey and/or providing personal information to us, you consent to transfer of your information to our facilities as described in this Privacy Policy.

### Right to Lodge Complaints

We are transparent about the ways in which we collect and use personal information, and welcome your questions and concerns. If you have any concern or complaint about the way we handle your personal information, please contact us as described below. To the extent you believe we have not addressed your concerns or otherwise choose to do so, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in the country where you reside and/or the United States. You may contact the US Federal Trade Commission regarding your concerns. For more information, please see <https://www.ftc.gov/faq/consumer-protection/submit-consumer-complaint-ftc>. If you reside in the European Union, you can also get more information by contacting the EU Data Protection Supervisor, please see <https://edps.europa.eu/data-protection/our-role-supervisor/complaints_en>.

### Website Security

Special attention is appropriately given to website security and the overall security of all data storage, processing, and transmission systems. This website, and its use as a data conduit, is protected by:

  * Firewalls with stateful packet inspection
  * Use of Secure Socket Layer (SSL) to protect data in motion
  * Use of encryption to protect data at rest
  * Regular vulnerability scanning to identify new threats
  * 24x7 monitoring and intrusion detection

### Further Information and Corporate Address

If you have any questions about the privacy statement and other policies outlined above, the practices of this site, or any other aspect of SkillSurvey, Inc., please contact:

SkillSurvey, Inc.  
Corporate Headquarters  
1235 Westlakes Drive  
Suite 330  
Berwyn, PA 19312  
Email: [customerservice@skillsurvey.com](mailto:customerservice@skillsurvey.com)

The foregoing policies are effective as of July 2, 2018. SkillSurvey reserves the right to change this policy at any time consistent with the provisions of this Privacy Policy and applicable law.

  * Terms of Use
  * Service Level Agreement
